export default Dpe5 = [
    {
        question: "1. Light is incident at angle 450 from air (n = 1) on a prism (n =\sqrt{2}). The angle of refraction is",
        options: ["600",
            "900",
            "300",
            "450"],
        correct_option: "300"
    },
    {
        question: "2. Which of the following lens is used to correct the defect of hypermetropia ?",
        options: ["Bi focal",
            "Bi concave",
            "Bi convex",
            "Plano convex"],
        correct_option: "Bi convex"
    },
    {
        question: "3. The power of accommodation for the normal eye is",
        options: ["400 D",
            "4 D",
            "40 D",
            "44 D"],
        correct_option: "4 D"
    },

    {
        question: "4. The phenomenon of light scattering in gases and liquids was explained by",
        options: ["Newton",
            "Faraday",
            "C.V raman",
            "Christian huygen"],
        correct_option: "C.V raman"
    },
    {
        question: "5. The common defects of vision are",
        options: ["All",
            "Presbyopia",
            "Myopia",
            "Hypermetropia"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "6. The phenomenon of scattering of white light by colloidal particle is known as",
        options: ["Dispersion",
            "Tyndall effect",
            "Beam of light",
            "Scattered light"],
        correct_option: "Tyndall effect"
    },
    {
        question: "7. p = 1/f \n" +
            "here 'f ' is",
        options: ["All",
            "Focus",
            "Focal lens",
            "Focal length"],
        correct_option: "Focal length"
    },

    {
        question: "8. The maximum and minimum focal length of the eye lens are",
        options: ["\frac{2.5 cm }{22.7 cm}",
            "\frac{25 mm }{22.7 cm}",
            "\frac{2.5 cm }{22.7 cm} and \frac{25 mm }{22.7 mm}",
            "\frac{25 cm }{22.7 cm}"],
        correct_option: "\frac{2.5 cm }{22.7 cm} and \frac{25 mm }{22.7 mm}"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Due to which molecule the sky appears white on summer days ?",
        options: ["H2o",
            "N2",
            "O2",
            "N2 and O2"],
        correct_option: "H2o"
    },
    {
        question: "10. Twinkling of stars is due to",
        options: ["Refraction",
            "Scattering",
            "Dispersion",
            "Reflection"],
        correct_option: "Refraction"
    },


    {
        question: "11. v = fλ here f is",
        options: ["Wavelength",
            "Frequency",
            "None",
            "Speed of wave"],
        correct_option: "Frequency"
    },
    {
        question: "12. The least distance of distinct vision is",
        options: ["Its value is 25 cm for healthy eye",
            "The value changes from person to person and with age",
            "All",
            "Its value never changes"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "13. Which of the following receptors in the retina of an eye identify the intensity of life ?",
        options: ["Optic nerve",
            "Cone",
            "All",
            "Rods"],
        correct_option: "Rods"
    },

    {
        question: "14. At which angle of scattering the intensity is maximum ?",
        options: ["45°",
            "0°",
            "30°",
            "90°"],
        correct_option: "90°"
    },
    {
        question: "15. Which of the following is unit of power of lens ?",
        options: ["Hertz",
            "Dioptre",
            "Mm",
            "Cm"],
        correct_option: "Dioptre"
    },
    {
        question: "16. Accommodation of eye lens is maximum at the age group of",
        options: ["10 - 15",
            "7 - 8",
            "16 - 40",
            "40 - 100"],
        correct_option: "7 - 8"
    },
    {
        question: "17. The splitting of-------------colour into different colours is called dispersion",
        options: ["Black",
            "Yellow",
            "Red",
            "White"],
        correct_option: "White"
    },
    {
        question: "18. The blue colour of sky is due to",
        options: ["Scattering",
            "Dispersion",
            "Reflection",
            "Refraction"],
        correct_option: "Scattering"
    },

    {
        question: "19. Pick out the coloured part that we can see in an eye ?",
        options: ["Iris",
            "Pupil",
            "Cornea",
            "Retina"],
        correct_option: "Iris"
    },
    {
        question: "20. What is the unit of Optical power ?",
        options: ["Newton",
            "cm",
            "Dioptre",
            "m"],
        correct_option: "Dioptre"
    },
    {
        question: "21. When white light passe through a dispersive medium, it breaks up into various colours, which of the following is true ?",
        options: ["Velocity of light is the same for all colours",
            "Velocity of light for violet is less than the velocity of light for red",
            "Velocity of light for violet is greater than the velocity of light for red",
            "Velocity of light for different colours"],
        correct_option: "Velocity of light for violet is less than the velocity of light for red"
    },

    {
        question: "22. When silver bromine exposed to sunlight silver turns to",
        options: ["Red colour",
            "Blue colour",
            "Light green colour",
            "Gray colour"],
        correct_option: "Gray colour"
    },
    {
        question: "23. The least distance of distinct vision for a young adult with normal vision is about",
        options: ["3 m",
            "25 cm",
            "2.5 cm",
            "25 m"],
        correct_option: "25 cm"
    },
    {
        question: "24. Which colour light travels faster in vacuum ?",
        options: ["Yellow",
            "All will travel with same speed",
            "Red",
            "Blue"],
        correct_option: "All will travel with same speed"
    },
    {
        question: "25. The process of re-emission of absorbed light in all directions with different intensities by the atom or molecule is called",
        options: ["Dispersion of light",
            "Scattering of light",
            "Refraction of light",
            "Reflection of light"],
        correct_option: "Scattering of light"
    },
]